听我呼唤
Hear me, ódinn,
奥丁 众神之父
All-Father of the gods.
召唤过去的阴影
Summon the shadows of ages past,
丝线织成网 诺伦三女神掌控所有人的命运 （注：掌管过去、现在和未来的命运三女神 织命运之网）
when the thread spinning Norns ruled the fates of men.
倾听一位王子对复仇的渴求
Hear of a prince's vengeance quenched
在熊熊燃烧的地狱之门得到满足
at the fiery Gates of Hel.
一个注定要去瓦尔哈拉的王子 （注：北欧神话中奥丁掌管的众神之厅）
A prince destined for Valh?ll.
听我呼唤
Hear me.
北欧人 翻译：Q （北大西洋）
他来了
He's here.
母亲 父亲来了
Mother, Father is here!
没有叫你 就不要踏入我的房间！
Never enter my chambers without invitation!
夫人 是国王
The king, milady. The king.
来吧
Come.
奥丁带他回家了
ódinn brought him home.
万岁 渡鸦王！
Hail, Raven King!
渡鸦战神 万岁！
War-Raven, hail!
吾王万岁！
Hail, my lord!
渡鸦战神 万岁！
War-Raven, hail.
万岁 赐环者！ （注：对国王的称呼 因为他们会把臂环/颈环赐给勇士）
Hail, ring giver!
前进 兄弟！
Onward, brother!
过来
Come here.
快走
Go.
万岁 奥凡迪尔 渡鸦战神！
Hail, King Aurvandil War-Raven!
万岁！
Hail!
就像斗犬回到主人身边
Like a battle-dog returning to its master,
我也回到了王后身边 被她美丽的锁束缚
I've come to be fettered by my queen's fair locks.
我们永远在一起 吾王
Ever are we bound, my lord.
阿姆雷特王子 （注：哈姆雷特的原型）
Prince Amleth,
你已经长大了 不能再以孩童之礼待你了
you have grown too old to be greeted as a child.
吾王万岁
Hail, Lord King.
但是...
But...
一位父亲永远不会老到
a father never grows too old
抱不动自己的孩子！
for a good smothering!
儿子 我太想你了
How I've missed you, my son.
你弟弟不来跟我们团聚吗？
Will your brother not grace us with his presence?
别想菲约尔了
Think not on Fj?lnir.
他很快会来找我们
He'll soon be with us.
我找到它的时候 它戴在一位王子的脖子上
This was worn round a prince's neck when I found it.
但它属于这位王子
But it was destined for this prince.
这是我的爱 要一直戴着
Wear it always with my love.
谢谢 父亲
Thank you, Father.
我的国王
My king.
菲约尔
Fj?lnir.
菲约尔回来了
Fj?lnir's back.
那个残暴之人回来了
The brute has arrived.
残暴之人回来了
吾王万岁
Hail, Lord King.
给这个残暴无情的屠杀者上酒
Furnish this fierce-hearted slayer of men with some drink,
我要与他共饮
that I might drink to him.
用我这杯吧 弟弟
Accept my cup, kinsman.
夫人
Milady.
快看 除了国王 王后的酒杯还沾了别男人的唇
Look how the queen's cup grows wet for more men than her king.
多贵重的金属才能买到一口浓烈的酒？
What metal might buy a fragrant sip?
美丽的银子
Sweet silver...
还是坚硬的铁棒？
or hard iron?
闭嘴 狗东西！
Silence, dog!
弗雷在上 你这是在侮辱你的国王和王后
（注：弗雷是丰饶之神）
By Freyr, you slander your lord and mistress!
好了 弟弟
Please you, brother.
他只是开个玩笑
'Tis but a jest.
玩笑？
A jest.
海米尔的嘴很脏
Heimir keeps a foul tongue,
但我仍把他当成真正的朋友
yet I keep him as a deep-sworn friend.
来吧 弟弟
Come, brother.
除了我 还有一个人需要你的保护
Here's one more in need of your safekeeping than myself.
索里尔
Thórir.
索里尔！
Thórir!
我的儿子
My son!
敬我的兄长 渡鸦战神！
To my brother, the War-Raven!
敬赫拉夫西王国！
To the Kingdom of Hrafnsey!
干杯！
Skál!
敌人尝到了我的鲜血
The enemy had a taste of my liver.
你受伤了？
Are you hurt?
阿姆雷特差点就成了我的继任者
Almost enough for Amleth to be marked my successor.
我今晚看到了他的天真无邪
I watched his innocence tonight.
他必须觉醒 为将来的命运做好准备
He must be awoken to what awaits him.
他还是个孩子
He is a puppy.
我祖父坐上铁王座的时候
He's the same age as my grandfather
跟他现在一样大
when he took the throne.
那不一样
That was different.
他要先杀掉他叔叔
He had to kill his uncle first.
你已经几个月没见到你的王后了
You have not seen your queen in a season.
来吧
Come.
让我带你去床上
Let me take you to our bed.
不
No.
我向幸运之神祈求 在伤口愈合之后
Pray my luck-spirits see me to many war fields
能让我再上许多次战场
after I defeat this wound.
我拒绝死于疾病
I refuse to die in sickness
也拒绝活得太久 慢慢老去
nor live the long life of a shameful graybeard.
我必须死于剑下
I must die by the sword.
我将死于荣耀
I will die in honor.
不用担心
Fret not.
吾王 你必将死于战场
You will die in battle, my lord.
瓦尔哈拉的大门在等着你 我知道
The Gates of Valh?ll await you, I know it.
我跟我父亲走过这条路
This is the same path I walked with my father
他跟他父亲也走过
and he with his.
现在 我们要一起走这条路
Now it is our path to walk.
奥丁
ódinn.
不要害怕 阿姆雷特
Be not afraid, Amleth.
跟我做
Do as I do.
谁在吠叫？
Who barks?
可是奥丁的双狼？
Is it the wolves of the High One?
还是村中的野狗？
Or is it the barking of the village dogs?
你们这些两脚犬 听我说
Harken to me, you two-legged dogs.
饮下知识酿成的蜂蜜酒
Drink the vision mead of knowledge.
学会何为生于荣耀、死于荣耀
To learn what it is to live and die in honor.
在战斗中杀戮
To be in battle slain
在死后回到瓦尔基丽的怀抱 （注：女武神）
and in death rewarded by the Valkyrjur's embrace.
少女战士会抱着你
The warrior maidens will carry you
走向闪着光的瓦尔哈拉之门
to the shimmering Gates of Valh?ll.
你们是想成为人的狗
You are dogs that wish to become men.
向我证明你不是狗
Prove you are not a dog.
你不仅是个人 而且吃得像个国王
Not only are you a man, you dine like a king.
你呢 幼崽 你是什么？
And you, little cub, what are you?
啊
Ah.
我闻到了一个聪明的学生
I smell a clever pupil.
在每条走廊上
At every passage,
都要四处张望
one should turn his eye round,
四处打探
one should spy round.
因为可能有敌人潜藏在附近
For a foe might be crouched within upon the floor.
每个人都要有足够的智慧
Wise in measure should each man be,
要有足够的智慧当个愚人
yet wise enough to be the fool.
Wise enough to be the fool.
告诉我 奥丁为什么会失去一只眼睛？
Tell me, how did ódinn lose his eye?
为了学习女人的秘密魔法
To learn the secret magic of women.
永远不要探寻女人的秘密 但要时刻留意
Never seek the secrets of women, but heed them always.
女人掌管着人类的秘密
It is women that know the mysteries of men.
是诺伦女神编织着人类的命运之王
The Norns that spin and weave at their Well of Fate.
-活在荣耀中 -活在荣耀中
-Live in honor. -Live in honor.
-守护你的家族血脉 -守护你的家族血脉
-Safeguard your familial blood. -Safeguard your familial blood.
阿姆雷特 奥凡迪尔之子 你知道这是什么意思吗？
Know you what that means, Amleth, son of Aurvandil?
如果我死于敌人剑下
Should I fall by the enemy's sword,
你必当为我复仇 或者永远活在羞愧中！
you must avenge me or forever live in shame!
我会的 父亲！
I will, Father, I will!
不割开敌人的喉咙
My blade will not rest
我就永远不会放下我的剑！
till it's drunk the blood from his open neck!
不要带着恐惧生活
Now live always without fear,
因为你的命运已定 而且你永远无法逃脱
for your fate is set and you cannot scape it.
发誓
Swear it.
我发誓
I swear.
这是你最后一次因为软弱而流下泪水
This is the last tear you will shed in weakness.
它会在你最需要的时候找上你
It will be given back when most you need it.
去看吧
Now, behold,
作为一个男人
as a man.
走近些 阿姆雷特
Approach, Amleth,
在我们的血液中看到国王之树
and in our blood behold the tree of kings.
父亲！
Father!
快跑！
Run! Run!
来受死吧 狗杂种！
Come for your carcass, you mongrels!
你惊讶地看着弟弟的眼睛
You behold your brother's gaze in amazement.
我就知道你会这样
I knew well you would.
可怜的是 你之前从未看过这个私生子的眼睛
Pity you never paid a bastard's eyes heed before.
现在仔细看着 你弟弟挥剑的动作多么干净利落
Now... behold how swiftly your brother swings his sword.
动手吧 弟弟
Strike, brother, strike.
但你要知道 就算戴上偷来的手环
But know that bearing a stolen ring
混血杂种也成不了国王
makes no half-breed a king.
它沾满了我的鲜血
Soaked in my blood,
很快就会像一条蛇一样 从你的手臂上滑下来
it will soon be sliding off your arm like a serpent.
你的王国不会长久
Your kingdom will not last.
让这罪行萦绕你活着的每一夜
Let this misdeed haunt your living nights
直到复仇之火在你的尸体上燃烧
till a flaming vengeance gorges on your death.
动手
Strike.
动手啊！
Strike!
为了瓦尔哈拉！
To Valh?ll!
奥凡迪尔国王已死！
King Aurvandil is dead!
菲约尔国王万岁！
-Long live King Fj?lnir! -Long live King Fj?lnir!
吾王万岁！
Hail, Lord King!
把那孩子的脑袋给我带来！
Bring me the boy's head!
你看到他了吗？
Do you see him?
-这边 -砍掉他的脑袋！
-Over here. -Cut him off!
我会轻一点的
I'll make it slow.
万岁 无兄者菲约尔！
Hail, Fj?lnir the Brotherless!
万岁 菲约尔国王！
Hail, King Fj?lnir!
菲约尔万岁！
Hail, Fj?lnir!
万岁 菲约尔国王！
Hail, King Fj?lnir!
菲约尔国王给自己找了个王后
King Fj?lnir has found himself a queen.
菲约尔！
Fj?lnir!
菲约尔！吾王！
Fj?lnir! My lord!
那个孩子
The boy!
The boy.
那个孩子死了
The boy is dead.
死在海里了
Dead in the sea.
对
Yeah.
像石头一样沉下去了
Sank like a stone.
父亲 我会为你复仇！
I will avenge you, Father!
母亲 我会救你！
I will save you, Mother!
菲约尔 我要杀了你！
I will kill you, Fj?lnir!
父亲 我会为你复仇！
I will avenge you, Father!
母亲 我会救你！
I will save you, Mother!
菲约尔 我要杀了你！
I will kill you, Fj?lnir!
父亲 我会为你复仇！
I will avenge you, Father!
母亲 我会救你！
I will save you, Mother!
菲约尔 我要杀了你！
I will kill you, Fj?lnir!
父亲 我会为你复仇！
I will avenge you, Father!
母亲 我会救你！
I will save you, Mother!
菲约尔 我要杀了你！
I will kill you, Fj?lnir!
为了瓦尔哈拉！
To Valh?ll!
不！
No!
干什么呢？
What are you doing?
过来
Come now, come. Come here.
Come here.
这些野蛮人很适合当奴隶
These savages make for fine chattel,
对吧 比约诺尔夫？
eh, Bj?rnulfr?
我们干得很好
We did good.
从没这么好过
Never better.
我们发现你的时候 你还是个孩子
When we found you as a cub...
那个时候我就知道 你的心冷如钢铁
...I knew then that you had a heart of cold iron.
太弱了！
Too weak!
我要强壮的！
I want strong ones!
不要弱小的！
Not weak ones!
妈妈！
Mama!
快吹啊 白痴！
Play, you idiot. Play!
我族人的屠戮者 徘徊在阴影中
Prowl in shadow, slayer of my people.
躲藏着
Hide.
虽然你的兄弟夺走了我的眼睛
Even though your brother stole my eyes...
但我仍能看到你
...I see you.
我没有兄弟
I am no one's brother.
成为一个永远不会哭泣的人是不够的
It is not enough to be the man that never cries,
阿姆雷特王子
Prince Amleth.
背弃了自己命运的王子
The prince that turned from his fate.
无所顾忌的野兽
A beast that cares for naught.
从人类眼睛榨取泪水的野兽
A beast that wrings tears from the eyes of men.
记住是谁看到你最后一次流泪
Now remember for whom you shed your last teardrop.
记住你要纠正错误的誓言
Remember the oath to right the wrong.
记住渡鸦王国
Remember the Raven King.
记住
Remember.
记住 它包含了你为了到达世界边缘
Remember, it contains the salty ocean
所穿越的茫茫大海
you must sail upon to the edge of the world.
它滋养了血管中流淌的冰冷仇恨
It feeds the freezing river of hate that runs in my veins.
它会带你去北方的岛屿
It will take you to an island in the north
那里会出现燃烧的湖泊
where there will spring a burning lake,
发源于黑山之巅
bursting from a black mountain's peak.
那里会淹死杀我父亲的凶手
There I will drown my father's killer.
跟着狐狸的尾巴 前往古老的居所
Follow the vixen's tail to the dwelling of the ancient one
找到命中注定的剑 搭配你无情的怒火
to seek the fated sword that matches your brutal rage.
女巫 为何要说出我的命运？
Why speak you my fortune, witch?
在你灰烬之路的尽头
For where your path of ashes ends,
是另一个人旅程的起点
another will begin her journey.
一位少女国王
A maiden king.
放开我
Release me.
你逃不开诺伦女神织成的命运之网
You cannot scape what fate the Norns have spun.
走吧！
Now begone!
这些奴隶去乌普萨拉
These slaves go to Uppsala.
这些送到基辅的市场
Those to the market in Kiev.
这些送到君士坦丁堡
Send them to Constantinople.
这些强壮的 就要一路送往
And these strong ones should make it all the way
菲约尔在冰岛的驿站
to Fj?lnir's post in Iceland.
菲约尔是谁？
Who is this Fj?lnir?
无兄者菲约尔
Fj?lnir the Brotherless.
他杀了自己的哥哥
So-called after he killed his brother,
可耻的奥凡迪尔国王 渡鸦战神
the disgraced King Aurvandil War-Raven.
我知道他
I know of him.
为什么要把他的奴隶送到冰岛？
Why are his slaves bound for Iceland?
菲约尔不是赫拉夫西的统治者吗？
Fj?lnir rules over Hrafnsey.
挪威国王哈拉尔夺走了他的王国之后
He fled to the backwater frontier with his wife and son
他就带着老婆儿子 逃到那个一毛不拔的地方了
after King Haraldr of Norway took his kingdom.
菲约尔杀了哥哥 到头了什么都没有
Fj?lnir killed his brother for nothing.
现在成了个牧羊人
Now he's a sheep farmer.
父亲
Father.
别担心
Worry not.
等我见到你的主人
When I meet your owner,
我会把你给我的温暖回报给他
I will thank him for the warmth you gave me.
把绳子拿来
Bring those two ropes.
回到你的位子上
Take your place.
他怎么会有这个数字？
Ah, how can he get that number?
他作弊了
He's cheating.
这是运气好
It is luck.
看看你有什么
Let's see what you've got.
又是这样
It continues then.
我把所有银子都输光了
I've lost all my silver, then.
你披上羊皮也不像羊 北欧人
Your sheep's clothing does not disguise you, Northman.
那要怎么办 聪明人？
What say you, spell speaker?
想要成为奴隶
You wish to be a slave,
就藏起你的狡诈
hide your cunning.
让牧羊人知道你是只羊
Show the shepherd you are a sheep.
我会让牧羊人知道什么是死亡
I'll show the shepherd his death.
抓紧！
Hold it strong!
站稳了！
Stay on your feet!
扎住我的手！
Take my hand!
我抓住你了！
I have you!
父亲 我会为你复仇
I will avenge you, Father.
母亲 我会救你
I will save you, Mother.
菲约尔 我要杀了你
I will kill you, Fj?lnir.
这边
Over there.
别管她了
Leave her here.
快走！
Move!
-好多尸体 -让他们烂掉吧！
- Bunch of corpses. - Let him rot!
海鸥会把尸体吃掉！
The seagulls will eat him!
它们很饿！
They're hungry!
快走 猪仔！
Move, swine!
你为什么要偷渡到这种恐怖的地方？
Why would you stow away to such a hellish place?
这块土地潜藏着恶魔
This ground harbors evil.
我的命运把我带到了这里
My fate has brought me here.
来找回我被偷走的东西
To find what was stolen from me.
是什么？
And what is that?
母亲 父亲 和王国
A mother, a father, a kingdom.
这是你的王国？
This is your kingdom?
叛徒偷走了我的王国
The traitor who stole my kingdom fled here
在被别的国王抢走后 他逃到了这里
when another king took it from him.
等我解决了他就会离开
I will leave when I'm done with him.
我是来自白桦林的奥尔加
I am Olga of the Birch Forest.
我也决心要逃离这个岛屿
And I, too, vow to escape this island.
那你将面临无数敌人
Then you must face many foes.
跟你一样
As do you.
你要独自面对敌人吗？
Would you face them alone?
你的力量能折断敌人的骨头
Your strength breaks men's bones.
而我的智慧能扰乱他们的心神
I have the cunning to break their minds.
你们俩 跟上！
You two, hold your traps!
快走！
Walk on!
我们为什么要做这些？
Why are we doing this?
什么？
What?
-这些 -什么？
-This. -What?
这是奴隶的工作
It's slave work.
你是首领
You're the chieftain.
这是你的宫殿
It's your temple,
而我是首领的继承人
and I'm the heir to this holy chiefdom.
没人知道下一个圣诞节
No man knows if he will celebrate next yuletide
自己会是国王还是奴隶
as a king or as a slave.
最好为两种命运都做好准备
Best to be prepared for both.
为了避免成为后者
And to stave off the latter, the least you can do
你至少可以让奴隶们知道 你跟他们一样强壮
is show your slaves you're as strong as they are.
但没人在看我们
But no one's watching us.
去喝点奶吧
Go fetch us some whey.
想想我的话
Think on what I said.
-防御手举高 -我举高了
- Keep your shield arm up. - I am.
-你没有 -我有！
- You're... - I am!
你没有
You are not!
进攻 哈提！
Attack, Hjalti!
不！
No! No!
菲约尔 吾王！
Fj?lnir, my lord!
你的货到了
Your shipment is here.
让我看看
Well, show me.
-其他的在哪？ -站起来！
- Where's the rest of them? - Get on your feet!
-站起来！ -站起来！
- On your feet! - On your feet!
站起来 猪猡
Up, swines!
排好队 杂种们！
Line up, bastards!
真可怜 都站不稳
Pitiful. Can't even stand.
他们活不过这个冬天
They won't last the winter.
全都卖掉吧
Sell all of them.
让我看看这个
Let me see this one.
我们有过更糟的奴隶
We've kept worse.
没什么好的
I'm not impressed.
臭气熏天
His stench.
永远不要直视我的眼睛 奴隶
Never look me in the eye, slave.
不知道在罗斯之国
Well, I wonder what they call a beast like you
他们怎么称呼你这种野兽
in the Land of Rus.
我叫…
I am...
比约诺尔夫
Bj?rnulfr.
听这个名字就知道他壮得像头熊
By name alone, you can tell he's as strong as a bear.
但如果你像头狼一样不可信
But if you're as untrustworthy as a wolf,
那我会亲手宰了你
I swear I'll put you down myself.
留下这个
We keep this one.
其他的可以带走了
The rest can go.
但是母亲需要两个人去厨房帮忙
But mother needs two for the kitchen
-还要一个洗衣服的 -走
- and one for the laundry. - Move.
还要两个男的种地
And two males for the harvest.
好吧
Fine.
这两个去厨房 她洗衣服
These two for the kitchen and her for the laundry.
再挑两个种地
And choose two males for the fields.
还有她
And her, too.
让她保持手臂白皙
Keep her arms white...
头发修长
...and her hair long.
打算爬出去吗 熊狼？
Plan to climb out, huh, Bear-Wolf?
就算你逃出了这个农场
Even if you did escape this farm,
也会成为蓝狐和赛尔基的食物 （注：海豹形的精怪 能蜕皮化成人形）
you'd only be carrion for the blue foxes and selkies.
这座岛就是一片废墟
This island is a barren waste.
你最好还是睡一觉吧
You best find yourself some sleep.
滚！
Get! Get!
Get!
偷东西的恶魔婊子
Thieving demon-bitch.
走开！
Away! Away.
快走开！
Away with you!
走开！
Away! Begone!
Away with you!
父亲 我会为你复仇
I will avenge you, Father.
母亲 我会救你
I will save you, Mother.
菲约尔 我要杀了你
I will kill you, Fj?lnir.
这里
Here. Go.
去撒尿吧
Go take a piss.
进去
In there.
停下
Stop there.
快进去啊！
You! Get on with it!
赶紧进去！
On with you now!
你傻了吗？
Where's your wits?
转弯
Turn around.
关上门
Shut the door.
你找到了吗？
Did you find it?
你丢的那些东西
What you lost.
你今天进屋的时候 找到了吗？
In the house today, was it there?
找到了
That...
还找到了更多
and more.
这是场噩梦
It's a nightmare.
那你就要醒来
Then you must wake up.
是他们的噩梦
It's their nightmare.
你！
You!
女人！
You, woman!
跟我们来！
You come with us!
你不属于这里！
You don't belong here!
菲约尔让你近身伺候
Fj?lnir wants you close.
如果把我弄丢了 你也会来找我吗？
If you lose me, will you come and look for me, too?
会吗？
Will you?
过来
Come here.
坐下 阿姆雷特 奥凡迪尔之子
Sit, Amleth, son of Aurvandil.
那个吃母鸡的朋友跟你说过我？
Did our hen-eating friend tell you of me?
不是
No.
是一个话更多的人
One much more talkative.
一个老傻瓜
An old fool.
可怜的海米尔
Poor Heimir.
他诉说着已逝之日
He speaks of days past
以及未至之时
and days yet to come.
菲约尔割下了他的舌头
Fj?lnir cut out his tongue,
剜出了他的眼睛 然后才杀了他
plucked out his eyes before killing him...
但我让他重生了
...but I made him ones anew.
好朋友
Kind friend.
我也会为你复仇
Know that I will avenge you, too.
我就怕你会说到我
I fear you must address me.
可惜 我没给他新的耳朵
Alas, I made him no new ears.
他的耳朵也被菲约尔割掉了
They also met with Fj?lnir's blade.
够了！
Enough!
你知道我为什么而来
You know why I have come.
你还是只穿着人类血肉的野兽
You are still a beast cloaked in man-flesh.
说吧 巫师
Speak, witch.
那好 奴隶！
So be it, slave!
漂泊的先知…
Wandering prophet...
从你的谋杀中…
...wake now...
醒来吧
...from your murder.
听我说！
Hear me!
海米尔来了！
Heimir is come!
你好呀 孩子
Hello, puppy.
我来寻找诺伦女神为我的复仇选定的武器
I seek the weapon the Norns of Fate chose for my revenge.
听着
Hear me.
由最危险的战争工匠锻造
Forged by the deadliest war-smiths
从巨虫的腹中爬出
ever to crawl from under the great worm's belly.
由最稀有的金属打造
A sword of the most secretive rare iron,
与霜巨人的骨头结合
bound with bone of the j?tnar.
在主人手中轻若鸿毛
Weightless in its owner's hand,
但又凶险如龙的毒牙
yet like a dragon's fang,
它永远锋利
its bite can never be dulled,
不断不弯
never broken nor bent.
它的锋刃只能在人类鲜血中淬火
Its blade could only be quenched in human blood.
它的战争烈焰举世无双
It is a battle flame like none other.
它的名字：
Its name:
德拉古尔
Draugr.
不死者
The Undead.
命中注定
It is fated.
德拉古尔
Draugr!
但是这把剑难以驾驭
Yet, difficult is the sword's nature,
只能在黑夜中出鞘
for it can only be unsheathed in the dark of night
或者在地狱的黑门前出鞘
or else at Hel's black gates.
地狱之门
The Gates of Hel.
正适合我的剑
There will my sword be just.
我会享受一直喂养德拉古尔 直到永夜降临
I will enjoy feeding Draugr till then in everlasting night.
那你也会享受 在对血亲的仁慈
Then shall you also enjoy the moment when you must choose
与对敌人的无情之间 做出抉择
between kindness for your kin or hate for your enemies.
无需抉择
That is nothing.
我的心里只有复仇
My heart knows only revenge.
让我看看
Show it to me.
你必须去拜访土丘居民
You must make a visitation to Draugr's owner,
德拉古尔的主人
the mound dweller.
好好记住满月的光芒
Mark well the full moon's light.
因为阴影并非好客的主人
For shadows are not hospitable hosts.
好好记住满月的光芒！
Mark well the full moon's light!
索里尔会选出我们中间最强壮的
Thórir will choose our strongest.
明天我们要证明 铁胡子哈康的人
Tomorrow we'll prove that Hákon Iron-Beard's men
是生于泥与水的人
are born of mud and water.
他们最后会化为泥土
Mud will be all that remains of them.
拉基！
Rakki!
拉基
Rakki.
把拉基带回家
Take Rakki home.
-你们两个… -拉基 过来
- And, you two... - Rakki, come.
都快天亮了 去睡觉
...it's nearly dawn. Get you to bed.
是 大人
Yes, my lord.
拉基
Rakki.
醒醒
Wake, you.
把她带过来 你知道是谁
Fetch her. You know the one.
是
Aye.
醒醒 奥尔加
Wake up, Olga. Wake up.
站起来
Get to your feet.
瓦尔基丽般的秀发
The hair of a Valkyrja...
却长在奴隶婊子头上
...on a savage Slav bitch.
一点血
A little blood.
肮脏的婊子！
Unclean whore!
调教好她 不然你们都要变成尸体
You will correct her, or you'll both be dead in the ground.
感谢诺伦女神
Thank the Norns that the woman's tide
今晚你的房里只有女人 懦夫
is the only blood that runs in your house tonight, coward.
我是愚者
I am a fool.
预言说我会在燃烧之湖中
It was foretold that I would slay my father's killer
手刃杀父仇人
in a burning lake.
在那天到来前
Till that day comes,
我要折磨那个让我坠入地狱的男人
I will torment the man who made my life a hell.
睡吧 黑夜之刃
Now sleep well, night blade.
是 我们都渴求复仇
Yes, we thirst for vengeance,
但我们都无法逃脱自己的命运
but we cannot escape our fate.
让他们排好队！
Get them in line!
要看起来有活力！
Look lively!
-快走！ -别偷懒！
-Move it! -Don't be idle!
那些不是给宴会准备的…
Those are for the feast...
他们要把我们带到哪里去？
Where are they taking us?
好像有关首领的宴会
Something about the chieftain's feast.
昨晚 我看到他跟你在一起
Last night, I saw him with you.
那你也知道 等我离开这座岛
Then you know Fj?lnir's touch will not linger on me
菲约尔的触碰不会留在我身上
when I leave this island.
你给了他一个教训
You marked him well.
我也找到了注定要杀掉他的兵刃
And I have found the cold iron that will strike him down.
-你什么时候动手？ -时间到了就动手
-When will you do it? -When I must.
现在 我要搅乱他的农场
For now, I will haunt this farm
像一具从坟墓里爬出来的饥饿尸鬼一样
like a hungry corpse returned from the grave.
菲约尔觉得阿姆雷特早就死了
Fj?lnir thinks Amleth is long dead.
对 但你母亲呢？
Yes, but what of your mother?
她会陶醉于菲约尔的痛苦中
She will revel in Fj?lnir's anguish.
她只是假装爱慕来保护他们的孩子
She only feigns her love to protect their child.
-也许她想… -等我救她出来
-Won't she wish... -When I free her,
如果需要的话 我会带上那个孩子
I will bring the boy if I must.
她们把我调回厨房了
They've moved me back into the kitchen.
-比约诺尔夫！ -如果我们能让他的人…
- Bj?rnulfr! - If we can keep his men...
我们的计划以后再说 走吧
Our plan will have to wait. Go.
比约诺尔夫
Bj?rnulfr, move!
-你到后面去！ -快走！
- You, to the back! - Move!
女人！
Woman!
索里尔大人 我们缺一个人
Thórir, my Lord, we're lacking one man.
我不是孩子了 别碰我的头发
I'm not a child. My hair is my own.
成年男人也需要女人来打理头发
I know grown men who need a woman to tend their hair.
让他们排好队
Get them in line.
你可以游戏之后再庆祝 奴隶！
You can celebrate after the games, slave.
有点活力！
Look lively!
大人
My lord.
过来！
Come on!
索里尔大人
Thórir, my lord.
会战斗吗 奴隶？
Can you fight, slave?
看着我的眼睛 奴隶
Look me in the eye, slave.
我问你会不会战斗
I asked you do you know how to fight.
这些是什么？
What are those?
你没见过击球游戏？
You've never seen a knatttré before?
入夜之前你就能见识到了
By nightfall, you'll have seen enough of them.
为了鲜血！
Play for blood!
你丢了我们家族的脸！
You're shaming our family's name!
我们需要更多人！
We need more men!
耶！
Yeah!
不！
No! No!
-贡纳！ -不！
-Gunnar! -No!
暂停游戏！
Halt the game! Halt it now!
别碰他！
Don't touch him!
-贡纳！ -暂停游戏！
- Gunnar! - Halt the game!
贡纳！
Gunnar! Gunnar!
愚蠢的小畜生！
Stupid runt!
不！
No!
-贡纳 -醒醒
- Gunnar. Gunnar. - Wake up. Wake up.
傻孩子 醒醒
Stupid, stupid boy. Wake up.
-贡纳 -贡纳
- Gunnar. Gunnar. Gunnar. - Gunnar.
醒醒
Wake up, come on.
贡纳 醒醒
Wake up, Gunnar. Wake up!
贡纳
Gunnar. Gunnar. Gunnar.
-贡纳 -醒醒
- Wake up. - Gunnar. Gunnar.
-醒醒！ -不
-Wake up! -No.
醒醒
Wake up.
我们赢了吗？
Did we win?
你真是首领的好儿子
Spoken like a true chieftain's son.
勇敢的孩子
A brave boy.
勇敢的年轻人
A brave young man.
你
You.
过来
This way.
你展示了自己的勇敢
You showed yourself brave
和忠诚
and loyal.
等我们回到农场
When we return to the farm,
你会得到一些特权
certain privileges will be granted you.
你不用再做那么多重活了
Your work will be less burdensome.
可以给其他奴隶分配工作
You will command others' burden.
还有 比约诺尔夫
And, Bj?rnulfr,
做为帮我们赢得游戏的奖励
as a reward for winning us the game,
我允许你给自己选个女人
I'll let you choose a woman for yourself.
你想选那个一直垂涎的婊子也行
Even that Slav bitch I've seen you eyeing.
父亲觉得她太…
Father found her too...
刚烈
...unyielding.
但是我们永远不会给你自由
But know that we will never make you a free man.
你永远抹不掉低贱奴隶的恶臭
The stench of a lowborn slave cannot escape him.
是
Yes.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们会怀念打扫茅厕的日子
We'll miss you cleaning the shithouse.
奥尔加
Olga.
你找到我了
You found me.
你走丢了吗？
Were you lost?
如果你在找我的话
Only if you were searching for me.
（土地母亲 请聆听女儿的祈祷）
（请告诉我 如何摧毁奴役我们的人）
（如何让我爱的人 免于愤怒与哀愁）
你在干什么？
What do you do?
命运的丝线在这里把我们绑在了一起
Here, where the threads of fate have bound us together,
我在这里拥抱树木 与大地对话
embraced beneath the trees, here I speak with the earth.
她跟你说了什么？
What does she tell you?
说了怎么接近你的母亲
How to reach your mother.
我的大地魔法会点燃你宝剑的火焰
My Earth magic will stoke the flames of your sword.
明天晚上 你和我…
Tomorrow night, you and I...
将开始这场噩梦
...will begin this nightmare
让菲约尔的生活陷入地狱
and bring Fj?lnir's life to chaos.
放进去
Finish.
回畜栏
Back to the stalls.
嘿
Hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
你
You.
弗雷的仆从
The servants of Freyr.
把它们放在国王的脚下
Lay them before our lord's feet.
你这个懦夫
You weakling.
不用怕
Fear not.
-后面会有很多人来陪你 -不
- You're the first of many. - No.
求你了！我们给你自由！
Please! We'll set you free!
我会找出来是谁干的
Oh, I will find who did this.
我会把他们找出来 然后把他们的眼球挖出来！
I will find them, and I will tear out their eyes!
把他们的舌头拔出来
And I will tear out their tongues!
他们将在地狱里哭泣！
They will all sup in Hel!
父亲 看！
Look, Father.
看他们对我的朋友们做了什么
Look what has been done to my brave friends.
基督教的怪物！
Christian monsters!
怪物！
Monsters!
无须男 是你干的吗？
Lack-beard, did you do this?!
回答我！
Answer me! Answer me!
行了！
Stop this!
儿子
Son.
冷静下来
Regain your calm.
他们都是好孩子
They were good boys.
弗雷在上 我们会为他们复仇
By Freyr, we will avenge them.
把他带走
Take him away.
索里尔说的对吗？
Is Thórir right?
会不会是那些基督教猪猡干的？
Could it be the Christian swines?
他们的神是一具钉在十字架上的尸体
Their god is a corpse nailed to a tree.
他们为什么要这样？
For what?
这些孩子从没惹过他们
These boys never touched them.
而且他们怎么会有武器？
And how might they find weapons?
不
No.
这些伤口不是我们这个世界的
These wounds are not of our world.
这个疯狂的灵魂会再次肆虐
This distempered spirit will ride again.
它带着一把饥渴的利刃
It wields a hungry blade.
走吧
Go.
我来准备祭祀
I will prepare a sacrifice.
去死吧！
On with you!
饮血的基督徒！
Blood-drinking Christians!
按吩咐去做
Do as you're told.
走
Go.
我有蘑菇
The mushrooms, I have them.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
灵魂将肆虐 会有更多鲜血
The spirits will ride and spill more blood.
黑暗的灵魂 退散
Black she-spirit, abate.
把祭品献给你的女主人
Bear this offering to your mistress
拴起你嗜血的猎犬
and sheath your rageful corpse-hound.
-拉基 -拉基！
- Rakki. - Rakki!
怎么了 拉基？
What is it, Rakki?
拉基！
Rakki!
拉基 趴下！
Down, Rakki!
拉基！
Rakki! Ra...
Rakki! Rakki!
放了她
Free her.
看起来弗雷自己做出了选择
Freyr, it seems, has chosen for himself
选中了应当牺牲之人
who is deemed fit for sacrifice.
被他的鲜血染红…
Blighted by his blood...
希望这能填饱他的胃口
Let us hope his hunger has been sated.
这不是我的神所为
This is not the work of my god.
这是巨魔的巫术
This is trollish sorcery.
今晚你们要武装起来守卫农场
Tonight, you will be armed to defend the farm,
因为这里也是你们的家
for this is also your home.
怎么能放心让他们来保护我们呢？
How can we trust them to protect us?
这里 狗东西
Here, dog.
你父亲不希望
Your father does not want an uprising
-奴隶暴动 -快走！
- by emboldened slaves. - Go!
不要质疑他的智慧
Do not doubt his wisdom.
快走！
Walk!
黑梦升起
Black dreams arise.
奴隶们 棒子不错嘛！
Hey, slaves, I like your sticks!
用那东西对抗恶魔？祝你们好运
Yeah, good luck fending off the demon with that thing.
给
Here.
饿吗？
Hungry?
今天晚上 你们才是食物！
Tonight, you are the food!
出去透透气吧
Go take some night air.
剩下的交给我
I'll finish here.
去啊
Go on.
-把它们弄走！ -快跑！
- Get them away! - Run!
她是个恶魔！
She's a she-devil!
不要碰他们
Touch them not.
别看他们的眼睛
Look not into their eyes.
暗夜幽灵进入了他们的皮肤
The night spirits have entered their skins
攫取了他们的心智
and are riding their minds.
索里尔！出来 迪希尔！
Thórir! Out, Dísir!
走开！
Begone!
我们黎明前跟你汇合
We will meet you before dawn.
父亲
Father.
下去吧
Leave me.
你的剑很长
Your sword is long.
别再说玩笑话了
Stop your jest.
我是你的儿子
I am your son.
阿姆雷特？
Amleth?
你还活着？
You live still?
生不如死
A life of death.
但我发过誓 至少要活到这一刻
Yet I swore to survive till this moment.
明天 我将在荣耀中完成我的誓约
Tomorrow, I shall finish my deeds in honor.
那时候我才能决定要不要继续活下去
Only then will I discover whether living is to my liking.
你是你母亲的儿子
You are your mother's son.
也是我父亲的儿子
And my father's.
我来为奥凡迪尔国王复仇
I am come to avenge King Aurvandil,
来让我背信弃义的叔父 呛死在自己肮脏的血液中
to choke my traitorous uncle in his death-blood...
来解救你
...and to free you.
看来你继承了你父亲的单纯
I see you have inherited your father's simpleness.
你说什么？
What say you?
我从未哀悼过他
I never mourned him.
你是他的王后啊
You were his queen.
你父亲容忍我
Your father endured me...
我因我怀着他的孩子
...because I bore him a son.
-不 -他的全部心思
-N-No. -His affections were
都放在银子和婊子身上了
only for silver and rutting his whores.
我甚至不知道 他到底有没有爱过你
I know not if he had heart enough to love you.
闭嘴
S... Silence.
他是个假装成国王的懦夫
He was a coward feigning to be a king.
他什么都不是
He was nothing.
只是一个自负又贪婪的奴隶
He was just another proud, lust-stained slaver.
别再说了！
Hold your tongue!
你在唾弃你的亡夫
You spit in the face of your dead husband.
但他的弟弟
Yet his brother...
他那美好的弟弟
...his fine brother.
一个对自己 和自己的毫不羞愧的私生子
A bastard has no shame of himself nor his trade.
你叔叔对我的过去了如指掌 但他仍然爱我
Your uncle loved me, though he knew well my past.
阿姆雷特
Amleth.
即使到现在 你仍然相信我给你讲的童话故事？
Even now, you believe the fairy tale I told you is true?
“来自布列塔尼的高贵新娘”？
"A noble bride hailing from the land of Brittany"?
我从来都不是他的新娘
I never began as his bride.
禽兽把我们抢去当了新娘
How easily we all become princesses again
我们就这样成了公主
when the beasts take us for their wives.
对
Yes.
你是你母亲被强迫怀下种
You were forced upon your mother.
而贡纳则是自由的爱的结晶
Gunnar was received freely with love.
不
No.
告诉你吧
And know you this:
是我跪下来求菲约尔
It was I who begged on my knees
他才同意杀掉奥凡迪尔
for Fj?lnir to kill King Aurvandil.
我用我的唇
I pressed my lips
吻上他强壮美丽的手
upon his strong, sweet hand.
我亲吻他 祈求他
I kissed it and I begged.
就是为了避免今天的到来
And so this day would never come,
菲约尔下令杀你
Fj?lnir ordered your death,
是得到了你母亲的祝福的
along with your own mother's blessing.
但是我看到了
But I saw it.
我看到菲约尔带走了你 你在尖叫
I saw Fj?lnir carrying you away... screaming.
尖叫？
Screaming?
我在笑
I was laughing.
撒谎！
Lies!
既然你已经来了 我们要怎么办？
Now that you are here, what do we do?
我应该杀了你 杀了你珍视的所有人
I should kill you and all that is dear to you.
但是你爱我
But you love me.
儿子爱母亲 母亲爱儿子
A son loves his mother and a mother loves her son.
而且你救了你弟弟的命
And you saved your brother's life.
你
You.
你爱…
You love.
你…
You...
爱
love.
除了我 没人真正了解你
None but me knows who you are.
你渴望复仇
And you are so hot for revenge,
从强暴中诞生的孩子
child born of savagery.
如果你杀了菲约尔
If you kill Fj?lnir...
如果你杀了索里尔
if you kill Thórir,
如果你野蛮到杀了我的贡纳
and if you are so untamed as to kill my Gunnar...
你将成为我的新国王 阿姆雷特
...you would be my new king, Amleth,
我们可以一起
and together...
统治王国
we will rule.
-贱人！ -你的品味和头脑
-Bitch! -Your taste and your mind
都跟你邪恶的父亲一样！
reek of your foul father!
你应该跟他一起去死！
You should have joined him in death!
你的话太恶毒了！
Your words are poison!
我就是你的死亡！
I am your death!
死吧！
Die!
你母亲呢？
Where is your mother?
告诉我
Tell me.
她在哪？
Where?
她跟菲约尔一样邪恶
She's as evil as Fj?lnir.
我要毁了他 毁了她爱的一切
I will destroy him and all that she loved.
我要化身钢铁风暴！
I will become a hailstorm of iron and steel!
我要复仇！
I will have my vengeance!
还要更多！
And more.
那我们现在要怎么做？
Then what must we do now?
我…
I... I...
我要去丘陵
I must take to the hills.
我母亲知道了我的身份 很快其他人也会知道的
My mother discovered who I am. Soon everyone will.
-我跟你一起去 -不
-I'll go with you. -No.
不能让他们知道你也参与了
They cannot know you are part of this.
早上起来 他们会追杀我的
Come morning, they will hunt for me.
为什么？
Why?
你杀了她？
You killed her?
我不会杀女人
I would not kill a woman.
哪怕是他
Not even her.
我的愤怒终结了索里尔
Thórir met his end by my fury.
总算摆脱他了
Well, good riddance.
明天晚上 你会回来杀掉菲约尔？
Tomorrow night, you will return and kill Fj?lnir?
如果诺伦女神允许
If the Norns of Fate allow it.
不管明天发生什么 你要准备好逃走
And whatever happens tomorrow, be ready to run.
他的心脏
His heart.
他的…
His...
他的心脏 他拿走了他的心脏！
His heart. It's taken his heart!
是什么魔鬼！
What evil is this?!
是什么魔鬼 吃掉了一个勇敢年轻人的心脏！
What evil eats the hearts of brave young men?!
弗雷 你听到了吗？
Freyr, do you hear me?!
冷静
Behave.
在手下面前不能这么失态
Be a man in front of your inferiors.
根本没有什么邪恶的灵魂
There is no evil spirit here.
我告诉你了
I told you. I told you.
是我那个被诅咒的儿子 阿姆雷特
It is my cursed son Amleth.
他小时候 我们就把他除掉了
We rid ourselves of him as a boy.
你一定要相信我
You must believe me.
他在这里
He is here.
奥凡迪尔的孽种还活着
The progeny of Aurvandil lives still.
恐怕是你死去哥哥的渡鸦之魂
I fear he was led here by the raven-spirit
把他带到这里的
of your dead brother.
-这不可能 -想想吧
-It's not possible. -Think.
他杀了你的手下
He's killed your men.
谋杀了你的大儿子
He has murdered your eldest son.
除非把你和我们的贡纳全都被杀死
And he will not rest till you lie cold in the ground
否则他是不会罢手的
and our own Gunnar lies slain beside you.
就是阿姆雷特
It is Amleth.
没有哪个神能帮你完成这个任务
No god can help you with this task.
你必须找到我儿子
You must discover my son
并亲手杀了他
and kill him with your own hands.
我知道你痛彻心扉 但听好我的话
Let my words be the whetstone to your biting rage,
昨晚的暴行不可能是一人所为
for the mischief of last night was not the work of one man.
找他跟他同伙的奴隶
Find the slaves who ally with him.
找到他们！
Find them!
跪下！
On your knees!
Down with you!
都跪下！
Down with the lot of you!
我不知道 也不在乎
I know not, nor care not,
那个奴隶有没有参与杀害我儿子
if that slave aided in the death of my son...
但如果不把你们知道的说出来
...but this is the end you will all meet
这就是你们所有人的下场
if you speak not what you know.
不说？
No?
看来你不再恐惧女人的鲜血了
I see you're no longer afraid of a woman's blood.
你
You.
当然是你了
Of course it is you.
菲约尔！
Fj?lnir!
放了她！
Let her alone!
我用你儿子的心脏换她的命！
I offer you your son's heart in exchange for her life!
我是熊狼阿姆雷特
I am Amleth the Bear-Wolf,
渡鸦战神奥凡迪尔国王之子
son of King Aurvandil War-Raven,
我是他的复仇使者！
and I am his vengeance!
杀了他！
Kill him!
把他带给我！
Bring him to me!
-杀了他！ -他是我的！
- Kill him! - He's mine!
有其父…
In the end...
必有其子
...you're just like your father.
恶魔会诞下恶魔
Evil begets evil.
你怎么知道这是你儿子的心脏
How do you know it's your son's heart...
而不是两天前被杀掉的疯狗的心脏？
...and not the heart of a rabid dog killed two nights ago?
它在哪？！
Where is it?!
你杀不了我
You cannot kill me.
就算你用剑捅我
Even if you were to strike me with your sword,
也杀不了我
it would not bite.
我的时候未到
It is not my time.
我会死在战场
I will die in battle.
我儿子的心脏在哪里？！
Where is my son's heart?!
奥丁 众神之父
ódinn the All-Father
会战胜你的勃起之神
will vanquish your god of erections.
惧怕他吧
Fear him.
住嘴！
Silence!
我会回来挖出你的心脏
I will come back for your heart.
然后跟你母亲一起把它吃掉
And your mother and I will eat it.
奥丁 让你的少女战士瓦尔基丽
ódinn, let the Valkyrja, your warrior maiden,
带我飞到你光辉的大门
fly me to your shining gates.
我看到了我的父母
I see my father and mother.
我看到了死去的血亲
I see my dead kindred.
我在弗雷亚的殿堂 看到了我的主人 （注：弗雷亚是爱神、战神与魔法之神）
I see my master in Freyja's hall.
他在召唤我
He calls me to him.
今晚我们将结束对索里尔的哀悼
Tonight, our mourning for Thórir ends.
哥哥 愿这匹神骏的战马
May the neck-ale of this swift steed
带你冲向武士之树的最高处
hasten you to the highest tree of the battle-weavers, brother.
我的悲恸
My hour of grief
结束了
has passed.
复仇怒火的燃烧
The time of wrath-kindled revenge
开始了！
is upon us!
这不是瓦尔哈拉？
This is not Valh?ll?
我没带你走那么远
I did not carry you that far.
我不是瓦尔基丽
I am no Valkyrja.
你的来世之梦要再等等了
The dreams of your afterlife must wait.
而且…
Besides...
我们的事还没结束呢
I'm not done with you yet.
我们命运带我来到了冰岛
My fate brought me to Iceland
践行我的复仇誓言
to carry out my pledge of vengeance.
但我的命运…
But my fate...
没让我做好遇见你的准备
...did not ready me for finding you.
我本来以为要永远冰封我的心脏
I thought I must always shield my heart in stone.
从来没想过我会对一个北欧人打开心扉
I could not think I would open it to a Northman.
为了让我逃跑 你牺牲了自己
You sacrificed yourself that I could flee.
而你也回来找我了
And you came back for me.
我从来没有跟一个人这么亲近过
I have never f-felt close to another person.
小时候也没有
Not since I was a child.
我诅咒你母亲的邪恶
I curse your mother's evil.
她杀死了我的过去
She murdered my past.
也许是你的诺伦女神
Could it not be that your Norns of Fate
重新给你编织了一条命运丝线呢？
have spun another thread for you to follow?
你的大地之神是怎么告诉你的？
What do your earth gods tell you?
让我无论去哪里都要带上你
That wherever I go, I must take you with me.
我在奥克尼有亲人
I have kinsmen in Orkney.
我们可以在那里找到安全的生活
We could find s... we could find safe passage there.
我们一起
Together.
但是我没法相信
Yet I cannot truly believe
你的复仇之火已经熄灭了
that you have extinguished your fire for vengeance.
我从前只知道仇恨
Hate is all I have ever known.
但是我希望自己能放下它
But I wish I could be free of it.
选择权在你
That is for you to choose.
我们去一起寻找未来吧
Let us find our future.
欢迎 水手们
Welcome, seafarers.
接下来的21天里
The deck of this wooden saddle-beast
你们能踏足的就只有这只猛兽的甲板了
will be the only ground you tread for 21 days.
如果幸运女神对我们微笑的话
我还以为会有更多菲约尔的人呢
I was expecting more of Fj?lnir's men.
本来他儿子也会加入我们
His son was to join us.
索里尔提前出发了
乘他自己的船
起锚！
Anchor up!
出发！
Sail down!
固定船索
Secure the shrouds.
船索已固定
Shrouds secured.
保持顺风行驶 舵手
Keep her downwind, helmsman.
是！
Aye, aye!
你的伤
Your wound.
跟我们的经历相比 这不算什么
It is nothing to what we have endured.
我已经把它忘了
I have forgotten it already.
我家族的血
My family's blood.
我自己的血 在你体内
My own blood is inside you.
你是我们王朝诞生的源泉
You are the well our dynasty will spring from.
在我能确定我们宝宝的安全之前
I did not wish you to know
我是不想让你知道的
until I could trust that our child would be safe.
只要菲约尔还活着 我们的孩子就永远不会安全
While Fj?lnir lives, our children will never be safe.
只要被他知道了
If he but knew of this,
他会带着众神之怒追杀你
he would hunt you with all the fire of the gods.
这不能再等了
It cannot wait.
停下
Stop this.
现在把我们绑在一起的是生命之线
There is now a living thread that binds us.
我真是个傻子
I was a fool.
我还以为能跟你一起逃离我的命运
I wished to flee with you from my fate.
我的幻象告诉我你会有两个孩子
My vision shows me you will have two.
而我的剑会保护他们
And my sword will save them.
但你要跟我们一起来啊
But you must come with us.
你一定要来！
You must!
预言说过我要做出抉择…
It was prophesied that I must choose...
在对血亲的仁慈 和对敌人的无情之间抉择
between kindness for my kin and hate for my enemies.
看看就在我们眼前的希望吧
And see what hope we have before us.
我两者都要
I choose both.
带她去奥克尼
Take her to Orkney.
带上这枚戒指 我的亲人会给你
In return for this ring, my kinsmen will give you
-九倍于它价值的报酬 -不！
-ninefold its worth. -No!
不！
No!
阿姆雷特！
Amleth!
你会成为国王的母亲
You will be mother to a king!
我们无法逃离命运
We cannot escape our fate.
不！
No!
阿姆雷特！
Amleth!
北风的女儿们 听我驾驭
带我前往我孩子祖先的岸边
我会在那里为你种下白桦林
无数枝条会跟风雨共舞
陶醉于你最公正的气息！
是那个奴隶！
It's the slave!
是他！
It's him!
关上房门！
Close off the house!
你曾经追捕的幼兽吃掉了你的鼻子
The cub you once hunted ate of your nose.
现在狼崽已经长大
Now the wolf is grown.
他饥肠辘辘 要把你整个吃掉
He hungers for the rest.
不管听到什么 你都要藏好
Whatever you hear, you must stay hidden.
保护他的安全
Keep him safe.
你们两个都要安全
Keep both of you safe.
我会的
I will.
你们自由了
Take your freedom...
想做什么就去吧
and do with it what you will.
菲约尔！
Fj?lnir!
绝不！
Never!
正中心脏
In the heart.
谢谢
Thank you.
母亲！
Mother!
我们在地狱之门见
I will meet you at the Gates of Hel.
在地狱之门
At the Gates of Hel,
你会找到我
you will find me.
你会死在那里
And there you will die...
死于杀死你父亲的双手
...by the hand that killed your father.
放开我！
Let me down!
（地狱之门）
死于兵刃
Slain by iron,
我们将在众神之父的厅堂重聚
we shall all meet again in the stronghold of the All-Father.
我的血脉将会延续
My blood will live on!
瓦尔哈拉在等着我！
Valh?ll awaits!
连接我们的丝线永远不会断裂
The thread that binds us can never break.
我们安全了
We are safe.
走你自己的路吧
Now make your passage.